Register of the Boutros Boutros-Ghali papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Charles Hill Advising and Projects File, 1969-2001 (Boxes 203-238)
  - Papers of the United Nations Secretary General, Boutros Boutros-Ghali (Yale University Press) (Boxes 224-238)
    - Project correspondence, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 232: 5)
    - Permissions to publish, 1998 (Box-folder 232: 6)
    - Drafts
      - Table of contents and introduction (Box-folder 232: 7)
      - Introduction, 2000 September (Box-folder 232: 8)
      - Fragments, 2000 September (Box-folder 232: 9)
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 232: 10)
      - Manuscript - unedited
        - 1992 (Box-folder 233: 1-4)
        - 1993 (Box-folder 233: 5-6, Box-folder 234: 1-2)
        - 1994 (Box-folder 234: 3-5)
        - 1995 (Box-folder 234: 6, Box-folder 235: 1-2)
        - 1996 (Box-folder 235: 3-4)
      - Manuscript - edited
        - 1992 (Box-folder 235: 5-6, Box-folder 236: 1-2)
        - 1993 (Box-folder 236: 3-6)
        - 1994 (Box-folder 237: 1-4)
        - 1995 (Box-folder 237: 5-6, Box-folder 238: 1)
        - 1996 (Box-folder 238: 2-3)
- Printed Matter, 1876-1975 (Box 239)
  Includes journals, magazines, and a published report. Arranged chronologically.
  - Statistique agricole et animale de l'Égypte pour l'année Copthe 1590, Ministère des Finances Égyptiènnes, 1876 (Box-folder 239: 1)
  - Pupikofer, Maxime and Alexandre Assabghy, Les accords de Montreux pour la suppression des capitulations et des tribunaux mixtes en Egypte, 1937 (Box-folder 239: 2)
  - L'Enragé, no.1, Comité d'action (Paris, France), 1968 (Box-folder 239: 3)
  - "Première histoire de la révolution de mai," L'événement, 29, 1968 June (Box-folder 239: 4)
  - Le Pave, no. 1, Comité d'Information Révolutionnaire, 1968 May (Oversize-box 289)
  - "L'observation militante: une alternative sociologique," Document / IDAC, Institut d'action culturelle, 9, Grand-Saconnex: Institut d'action culturelle, 1975 (Box-folder 239: 5)
  - Unidentified fragment (Arabic), undated (Box-folder 239: 6)
- Writings by Others, 1876-1910 (Boxes 239-246)
  Includes original writings by Kamel Ghali and Mikhail Sharubim, Boutros-Ghali's maternal grandfather.
  - Kamel Ghali, "Essai sur l'agriculture de l'Égypte" and related documents, 1889; Original handwritten copy and printed copy. (Box-folder 239: 7-8)
  - Mikhail Sharubim, 1890s? (Boxes 239-246)
    Original handwritten manuscript.
    - Invoice log, undated (Box-folder 239: 9)
    - al-kafi fi tarikh Misr al-qadim wa al-hadith [The Definitive Guide for Ancient and Modern Egyptian History]
      - Volumes 1-4 (Box-folder 239: 10-11)
        Handwritten manuscript. Loose pages, most unnumbered.
      - Volumes 1-4 (cont'd.) (Boxes 240-245)
      - Volume 5 (Boxes 245-246)
        Bound volumes.
- Boutros-Ghali Family Archive, 1867-1982 (Boxes 247-279)
  Includes photocopies of clippings, correspondence, reports, photographs, and writings. Original classification scheme has been retained.
  - Boutros Ghali Pasha
    - B/1. Assassination of Boutros Ghali Pasha [Questions derivant de l'assassinat de Boutros-Ghali], 1910-1912
      - Newspapers and newspaper clippings, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 247: 1-7, Box-folder 248: 1-5)
        Includes some clippings on Theodore Roosevelt's visit to Egypt in 1910.
      - Condolences, 1910 (Box-folder 248: 6-7)
      - Botrossia Church, clippings, 1912 (Box-folder 248: 8)
    - B/7. Assassination of Boutros Ghali Pasha
      - Newspaper clippings, 1910 (Box-folder 249: 1)
      - Condolences and related correspondence, 1910 (Box-folder 249: 2)
    - B/2. Political notes and correspondence on the government of Boutros Ghali, 1898-1910 (Box-folder 249: 3)
    - B/3. Meglis Milli, writings, 1898-1903 (Box-folder 249: 4)
    - B/3. Coptic concerns, correspondence and memoranda, 1906 (Box-folder 249: 5)
    - B/3. Journaux egyptiens [Egyptian newspapers], 1908-1914 (Box-folder 249: 6-7)
    - B/4. Ghali Bey Norouz (father of Boutros Ghali Pasha) papers and correspondence, 1889 (Box-folder 249: 8-9)
    - B/5. "The Destitution of the Towara Bedouins at Mount Sinai: Facts and Observations Collected By a Traveller in the Sinaitic Peninsula,", circa 1887 (Box-folder 249: 10)
    - B/5. Origins of the Ghali family, notes, undated (Box-folder 249: 11)
      Includes photocopies of photographs.
    - B/6. Newspapers relating to the National Party and Mustafá Kamil, 1908 (Box-folder 250: 1-2)
    - B/8. Dinshaway incident, 1908 (Box-folder 250: 3)
    - B/8. Correspondence with Lord Cromer, Eldon Gorst and other British officials in Egypt, 1906-1910 (Box-folder 250: 4)
    - B/9. Letters from Lord Cromer, 1894-1906 (Box-folder 250: 5)
    - B/11. Diplomatic concerns with Turkey, 1909 (Box-folder 250: 6)
    - B/11. Correspondence regarding the Sublime Porte (Ottoman Porte), 1891 (Box-folder 250: 7)
    - B/11. References des citations concernant Boutros Pacha dans Misr, 1884 (Box-folder 250: 8)
    - B/12. Khedive Cabinet correspondence, reports, and related materials, 1904-1909 (Box-folder 250: 9-12)
    - B/13 (II). Diplomatic correspondence concerning foreign affairs, 1882-1909 (Box-folder 251: 1)
    - B/14. Legislative Council of Egypt documents, 1908 (Box-folder 251: 2)
    - B/15. Financial reports for the Egyptian Minister of Finance and related correspondence, 1880-1909 (Box-folder 251: 3-5)
    - B/17. Suez Canal, undated (Box-folder 251: 6)
    - B/18. Correspondence with Ahmed Hechmet Pacha, Ahmed Mazloumi Pacha, Sir Reginald Wingate, Rudolf Carl von Slatin, and others, 1881-1909 (Box-folder 251: 7)
    - B/19. Correspondence with Lord Cromer and other British officials in Egypt, 1895-1910 (Box-folder 251: 8-9)
    - B/19. Press laws in Egypt, 1909 (Box-folder 251: 10)
    - B/20. Family correspondence, 1899-1909 (Box-folder 251: 11-13)
      Mostly letters from Boutros Ghali Pasha to his children.
    - B/21. Letters from Mohammed Cherif, 1903 (Box-folder 252: 1)
    - B/22. Certificate from Mason's guild, 1882 (Box-folder 252: 2)
    - B/23. Tributes and articles in remembrance of Boutros Ghali Pasha, 1910-1902 (Box-folder 252: 3-5)
    - B/24. Riaz Pasha and Mohammed Cherif correspondence, 1894 (Box-folder 252: 6)
    - B/25. Al Azhar, 1907-1909 (Box-folder 252: 7)
    - B/26. Correspondence and invitations concerning official visits, 1895-1905 (Box-folder 252: 8)
    - B/28. Certificates and honors, 1894-1902 (Box-folder 253: 1)
    - B/30. "Attributions des inspecteurs d'irrigation et des Moudirs: Rapports qui doivent exister entre ces fonctionnaires" and related correspondence of Colonel Scott Moncrieff, 1886 (Box-folder 253: 2)
    - B/31. Administrative reports from different government ministries, 1904 (Box-folder 253: 3)
    - B/32. Correspondence regarding new Port of Alexandria, 1893 (Box-folder 253: 4)
    - B/33. Alexandria Government, European Criminal Bureau correspondence, 1907-1908 (Box-folder 253: 5)
    - B/34. Report on expropriations of the Cairo Electric Railways and Heliopolis Oases Company, 1908 (Box-folder 253: 6)
    - B/35. Remarks on the amendment of the penal code, 1904 (Box-folder 253: 7)
    - B/36. Riots in Alexandria, 1897 (Box-folder 253: 8)
    - B/37. Quarantine stations in El-Tor, 1890-1891 (Box-folder 253: 9)
    - B/38. Constitution of the Society of "General Land Corporation,", 1909 (Box-folder 253: 10)
    - B/39. Mixed Tribunal report, 1898 (Box-folder 253: 11)
    - B/40. Memoranda issued by Administration des domaines de l'etat, 1893 (Box-folder 253: 12)
    - B/41. Regulation of cadastre, 1888 (Box-folder 253: 13)
    - B/42. Notes of the Finance Committee, 1887 (Box-folder 253: 14)
    - B/43. Problems of inland waterways (Box-folder 253: 15)
    - B/44. Reorganization of La Santé, 1880 (Box-folder 253: 16)
      Includes original document.
    - B/45. List of criminal infractions in Egypt, 1908 March 10-15 (Box-folder 253: 17)
    - B/46. Congratulations, 1908 (Box-folder 253: 18)
    - B/47. Writings on the regulation of the legal profession, 1893 (Box-folder 253: 19)
    - B/48. "Memorandum Prepared on Behalf of Certain Members of the Khedivial Family for Consideration by Sir Eldon Gorst K.C.M.G. His Majesty's Agent and Consul General,", circa 1908 (Box-folder 253: 20)
    - B/49. Program advertising shares of a railway connecting the suburbs of Coubeh-les-Bains to Matarieh, 1888 (Box-folder 253: 21)
    - B/50. Report on the public debt of the Egyptian government, manuscript, 1891 (Box-folder 254: 1)
    - B/51. Memoranda of the Egyptian finance minister, 1909 (Box-folder 254: 2)
    - B/52. Expropriations for creating a new road, 1909 (Box-folder 254: 3)
    - B/53. Accounts and reports of Boutros Ghali's properties, 1893 (Box-folder 254: 4)
    - Typhus in Egypt, 1898 (Box-folder 254: 5)
  - B/N/W
    - International newspaper clippings, 1910 (Box-folder 254: 6-7)
      Relates mostly to the assassination of Boutros Ghali Pasha.
    - BNW/1. Capitulations, undated (Box-folder 255: 1-2)
    - BNW/2. Suez Canal, 1888-1926 (Box-folder 255: 3-5)
      Relates to the history of the Suez Canal, including the Convention of Constantinople and the Treaty of 1888, and the use of the Suez Canal during the Spanish American war.
    - BNW/4. Clippings on the Suez Canal, 1910 (Box-folder 255: 6)
    - BNW/5. "L'arrangement Franco-Anglais," La Depeche coloniale illustrée, 1904 (Box-folder 255: 7)
    - BNW/6. Questions administratives, 1885-1891 (Box-folder 255: 8-9)
      Reports and other documents relating to public instruction, hospitals, pension laws and other policy matters.
    - BNW/7. Newspapers and newspaper clippings on Coptic Christians, Egyptian nationalists, and the assassination of Boutros Ghali, 1901-1914 (Box-folder 255: 10, Box-folder 256: 1-3)
    - BNW/9. Printed matter relating to Egyptian politics and law, 1867-1911 (Box-folder 256: 4, Box-folder 257: 1-2)
      Some inscribed to Boutros Ghali Pasha.
    - BNW/10. Theater programs, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 257: 3)
  - C/1.I. Questions Coptes, 1884-1909 (Box-folder 257: 4, Box-folder 258: 1-2)
    Includes correspondence, memoranda, government documents, notes, and printed matter relating to issues concerning Coptic Christians in Egypt.
  - C/2.II. Questions Coptes, 1892, undated (Box-folder 258: 3-7)
  - C/3.III. Questions Coptes, 1891-1908 (Box-folder 259: 1-2)
  - D, 1870-1904 (Boxes 259-262)
    - D/1. Sous Commission de la Réforme Judiciaire, reports and protocols, 1884 (Box-folder 259: 3)
    - D/2. Commission internationale instituée pour l'examen des propositions du gouvernement Égyptien tendant a réformer l'administration de la justice en Égypt, minutes and report, 1870 (Box-folder 259: 4)
    - D/3. Commission Internationale de la Réforme Judiciaire (Tribunaux Mixtes), protocols, minutes, and other reports, 1890-1899 (Box-folder 259: 5, Box-folder 260: 1)
    - D/4. Sous Commission de la Réforme Judiciaire, report, 1884 (Box-folder 260: 2)
    - D/5. Commission Technique Internationale de la Réforme Judiciaire, minutes 1-4, 6-8, 1890 (Box-folder 260: 3)
    - D/6. "Rapport presente a son excellence monsieur le ministre des affaire étrangères par la commission instituee a l'effet d'examiner les propositions faites par le gouvernement Égyptien pour réformer l'administration de la justice en Égypte,", 1890 (Box-folder 260: 4)
    - D/7. Sous Commission de la Réforme Judiciaire (Proces Mixtes), reports, 1880 (Box-folder 260: 5)
    - D/8. Sous Commission de la Réforme Judiciaire, reports and minutes, 1881 (Box-folder 260: 6-7)
    - D/8. Sous Commission de la Réforme Judiciaire, minutes 1-15, 18-19, 21-22, 24, 28, 1904 (Box-folder 261: 1)
    - D/8. Ministry of Justice reports, 1904 (Box-folder 261: 2)
    - D/9. Administration of Daira Sanieh and other estates in Egypt, printed matter and reports, 1875-1883 (Box-folder 261: 3-6, Box-folder 262: 1)
      Includes "Ismail-Pacha Saddick, ou, La mort du mouffetich," Biographies Egyptiennes (1879).
    - D/10. Reports of cases seen by the Court of Appeals of Alexandria and reports on judicial reform, 1887 (Box-folder 262: 2-4)
  - Ethiopia
    Includes materials relating to the Ethiopian Orthodox Coptic Church and its relationship with the Egyptian Coptic Church. Includes correspondence of the beatitude Kyrillos VI, Abuna Bassilos, Haile Selaisse, and decrees, reports, clippings, printed matter, and other church documents.
    - General, press releases of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Provisional Military Government of Socialist Ethiopia, maps, and newspaper clippings, 1978 (Box-folder 263: 1)
    - Ethiopia 1, reports of the Committee for the Defense of the Ethopian Cause, clippings and summaries relating to the Italian invasion of Ethiopia, aid to Ethiopia, and correspondence of the Coptic pope and patriarch of Alexandria, Youannes, with Haile Selassie and British Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs, Anthony Eden, 1936-1941, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 263: 2-4)
    - Ethiopia 2 - Part 1, includes correspondence between Haile Selassie, 1936-1969 (Box-folder 263: 5, Box-folder 264: 1-2)
    - Ethiopia 2 - Part 2, includes correspondence of the Coptic Church, photographs (photocopies) of Pope Kyrillos VI and Gamal Abdel Nasser, 1930-1971 (Box-folder 264: 3-5)
    - Ethiopia 3, 1940-1948 (Box-folder 264: 6-7, Box-folder 265: 1-3)
      Includes Governo Generale Dell'Africa Orientale Italiana, Regolamento della chiesa d'Etiopia (1940).
    - Ethiopia 4, 1955 September-November (Boxes 265-266)
      - Clippings and memoranda relating to the Ethiopian Orthodox patriarch and to the revised constitution of Ethiopia, 1955 September-November (Box-folder 265: 4-6)
      - Notes and memoranda of Mirritt Boutros Ghali relating to property rights and government administration in Ethiopia, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 266: 1)
        Includes curriculum vitae of Mirrit Boutros Ghali.
    - Ethiopia 5
      - Public statements of Kyrillos VI, pope of Alexandria, and correspondence of Mirritt Boutros Ghali and Dejazmach Asrate Kassa, and other materials, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 266: 2)
      - Clippings on removal of Pope Aba Youssab by the Archbishop of Ethiopia, Abuna Basilios, and the death of Aba Youssab, and other materials, 1946-1956 (Box-folder 266: 3)
      - Suspension and abdication of Pope Abba Yousab II, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 266: 4-5)
    - Ethiopia 6
      - Ecumenical council correspondence and reports, 1955 (Box-folder 267: 1)
      - Newspaper clippings on the enthronement of the patriarch, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 267: 2-3)
      - Visit of Kyrillos VI (1960) and Shenouda III to Ethiopia (1973), 1960-1973 (Box-folder 267: 4)
    - Ethiopia 7, writings, memoranda, and printed matter concerning the relationship between the Egyptian and Ethiopian Coptic churches, 1946 (Box-folder 267: 5-6)
    - Ethiopia 8 (Box 268)
      - Bulletins and pamphlets relating to Coptic Christians in Ethiopia, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 268: 1)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 268: 2-4)
    - Ethiopia 9
      - "File A," clippings on the political situation in Ethiopia, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 269: 1-2)
      - "File B," clippings and correspondence on the political situation in Ethiopia, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 269: 3)
        Includes materials from the All Africa Conference of Churches.
    - Ethiopia 10
      - The Derg, speeches of Haile Selassie, and documents pertaining to the Ethiopian political program, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 269: 4-5)
      - Newspapers, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 270: 1)
    - Ethiopia 11
      - Ethiopian Herald newspapers, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 270: 2-5)
      - Newspapers and clippings (Box-folder 271: 1-4)
      - Speech by Haile Selassie and other collected writings on Ethiopia, 1955-1966 (Box-folder 271: 5)
      - Africa magazine feature on Ethiopia, 1975 January (Box-folder 271: 6)
    - Ethiopia 12
      - Clippings on foreign ministers in Ethiopia, 1974 (Box-folder 272: 1)
      - Political organizations, political prisoners, and other human rights issues, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 272: 2)
      - J'Informe newspaper, 1977 November 15 (Box-folder 272: 3)
    - Ethiopia 13
      - Proclamation nos. 7, 8, 9, and 10, Negarit Gazeta, 1974 (Box-folder 272: 4)
      - Newspaper clippings and pamphlet on human rights violations in Ethiopia, 1974, 1978 (Box-folder 272: 5)
      - Correspondence of Mirritt Boutros Ghali, 1977 (Box-folder 272: 6)
      - Clippings on the deposition of emperor Haile Selassie, 1974 September (Box-folder 272: 7, Box-folder 273: 1-2)
    - Ethiopia 14, clippings and correspondence on the Ethiopian civil war, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 273: 3-4)
    - Ethiopia 15 - Deir El-Sultan
      - Newspaper clippings, 1961 (Box-folder 274: 1)
      - Architectural plans, 1961 (Box-folder 274: 2)
      - Petridis, S. Pierre, "La présence Ethiopienne a Jerusalem: Son statut juridique et ses droits de propriete sur le monastere de Dar-Es-Sultan,", 1961 June (Box-folder 274: 3)
      - Meinardus, Otto, "A History of the Ethiopians in the Holy Land,", 1962 (Box-folder 274: 4)
      - Meinardus, Otto, The Copts in Jerusalem, 1960 (Box-folder 274: 5)
      - "The Rights of the Abyssinian Church in the Holy Places," documentary authorities, vol. 2, circa 1959-1972 (Box-folder 274: 6)
      - Correspondence of Mirritt Boutros Ghali, 1961 (Box-folder 274: 7)
      - Tedeschu, Salvatore, "Profilo Storico di Dayr as-Sultan," Journal of Ethiopian Studies, 1964 July (Box-folder 274: 8)
      - Zander, Walter, "Jurisdiction and Holiness: Reflections on the Coptic Ethiopian Case," Israel Law Review, 1982 (Box-folder 274: 9)
  - Mirrit Boutros Ghali, 1927-1958 (Boxes 274-276)
    See also: Ethiopia.
    - Writings and correspondence on agrarian reform in Egypt, 1946-1953 (Box-folder 274: 10)
    - References and statistics on agrarian reform, 1945-1957 (Box-folder 275: 1-2)
    - Writings on economic crisis, 1956 (Box-folder 275: 3)
    - Writings on Copts in Egypt (al-Aqbat fi Misr), 1979 (Box-folder 275: 4)
    - Memoranda from former minister Farid Antoun to Mirrit Boutros Ghali, nos. 1-24, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 275: 5-6)
    - Miscellaneous reports, writings, and correspondence on economic conditions and other topics, 1943-1958 (Box-folder 276: 1)
    - Miscellaneous documents. Includes a report on the Black Tea Menace in the Fayoum Province, diary extracts on the Red Crescent Mission to Esna, a project proposal relating to agrarian reform law, and unidentified writings on Ethiopia, 1927-1945 (Box-folder 276: 2)
  - Naguib Boutros Ghali (Boxes 276-277)
    Includes the papers of Naguib Boutros Ghali's wife, Anna.
    - N/1-N/1A. Correspondence, 1890-1915 (Box-folder 276: 3)
      Includes letters from Hussein Ruchdi Pacha, Percival Elgood, F. Charles Roux, Mohammed Cherif and others.
    - N/2. Certificates and dissertation, 1873-1902 (Box-folder 276: 4)
    - N/2A. Academic correspondence, 1883-1889 (Box-folder 276: 5)
    - N/3. Correspondence of Naguib Ghali Pasha and Anna Naguib Boutros Ghali (wife), 1910-1921 (Box-folder 276: 6)
    - N/3A. Invitations and menus from dinner receptions, 1907-1939 (Box-folder 276: 7)
    - N/4. Correspondence with Boutros Ghali Pasha (father), 1892-1908 (Box-folder 276: 8)
    - N/5. Honors and decorations, 1905-1910 (Box-folder 276: 9)
    - N/6-7. Correspondence, 1897-1908 (Box-folder 276: 10)
    - N/8. Newspaper clippings on the death of Naguib Ghali, 1933 (Box-folder 277: 1)
    - N/9. Anna Naguib Boutros Ghali correspondence, 1903 (Box-folder 277: 2)
    - N/10. Letter to President Theodore Roosevelt from Naguib Ghali, circa 1905 (Box-folder 277: 3)
    - N/11. Condolences, 1933 (Box-folder 277: 4)
    - N/12. Elias Awad correspondence, 1912 (Box-folder 277: 5)
    - N/13. Marriage, 1907 (Box-folder 277: 6)
    - N/14. Anna Naguib Boutros Ghali correspondence, 1902-1933 (Box-folder 277: 7)
    - N/16. Writings on the Armenian question and letters to Anna Naguib Boutros Ghali, 1915-1933 (Box-folder 277: 8)
  - P
    - P/1. Letter from Lord Dufferin to Mohammed Cherif, 1883 (Box-folder 277: 9)
    - P/2. Réclamation de LL. AA. les Princes et Princesses Contre le Gouvernement Égyptien Concernant le Solde de la Liquidation de l'Actif de la Daira Sanieh: Memoire en Défense et Conclusions Pour le Gouvernement Égyptien, 1906 (Box-folder 277: 10)
    - P/3. Personal notes of Sir Ronald Storrs, 1930 (Box-folder 277: 11)
    - P/5. Translation of letter from Sir Granville to Sir Edward B. Malen, 1881 (Box-folder 277: 12)
    - P/7. Daira Sania, undated (Box-folder 277: 13)
    - P/8. Letters on diplomatic and administrative concerns over foreigners in Egypt, 1895-1900 (Box-folder 277: 14)
    - P/9. Boutros Ghali Pasha miscellaneous documents, 1881-1882 (Box-folder 277: 15)
  - Report by Ahmet Zaki on the Constantinople Library, 1909 (Box-folder 277: 16)
  - Sadeq Henen Pasha
    - S/1. Memoirs, 1968 (Box-folder 277: 17)
    - S/2. Reports from London to Wacyf Ghali, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 278: 1)
  - Sinai Peninsula and administration of Taba territory, correspondence and reports, 1903 (Box-folder 278: 2)
    Includes letter from the sharif of Mecca.
  - U/1. Numero illustré du journal du Caire, 1909 January (Box-folder 278: 3)
  - W. Reports, correspondence, and newspaper clippings relating to the Sudan question and to the murder of Sir Lee Stack, 1930 (Box-folder 278: 4)
  - Wacyf Boutros Ghali
    - W/1. Saad Zaghloul correspondence, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 278: 5)
    - W/1A. Family correspondence, 1897-1904 (Box-folder 278: 6)
    - W/2. Correspondence, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 278: 7)
      Includes copy of Révélations relatives à la situation intérieure de l'Egypte: 5 lettres sur le "élections" imminentes échangée entre le Prince Aziz Hassan et le Dr. Mansour Rifat.
    - W/3-4. Wafd ministers, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 278: 8)
    - W/7. Correspondence and clippings from Saad Zaghloul's trip to Europe, 1924 (Box-folder 278: 9)
    - W/9.2. Documents relating to the 1924 negotiations between Saad Zaghloul and Ramsay MacDonald (Box-folder 278: 10)
    - W/11. Clippings about Wacyf Boutros Ghali and the nationalist movement in Egypt, 1924-1948 (Box-folder 278: 11)
    - W/14. Official vists and invitations, 1937 (Box-folder 278: 12)
    - W/15. Deaths of Wafd party members in prison and in exile, clippings, 1923-1937 (Box-folder 279: 1)
    - W/16. Documents relating to Saad Zaghloul, the request for admission of Egypt to the Treaty of Lausanne, and the court trial of members of the Egyptian delegation, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 279: 2)
    - W/17. Nationalist movement, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 279: 3)
    - W/18. Record of sales of books written by Wacyf Boutros Ghali, 1923 (Box-folder 279: 4)
    - W/19. Diplomatic relations with Italy, 1924 (Box-folder 279: 5)
    - W/20. Articles and reviews of writings, 1914-1948 (Box-folder 279: 6)
    - W/22. Wafd party, 1932 (Box-folder 279: 7)
    - W/25. Official visits and invitations, 1937 (Box-folder 279: 8)
    - W/30. "Memorandum on the Negotiations of 1929 Which Led to the Anglo-Egyptian Project Treaty,", 1936 (Box-folder 279: 9)
    - W/31. Documentation on the mixed courts in Egypt and correspondence with European legations in Cairo, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 279: 10)
    - W/35. Newspaper clippings, 1924 (Box-folder 279: 11)
    - W/38. Notes and clippings on the Wafd opposition and the government of Sidky Pasha, 1931 (Box-folder 279: 12)
    - W/39. Drafts of literary writings, 1908-1924 (Box-folder 279: 13)
    - W/40. Clippings on Zionism and the Palestinian question, 1929 (Box-folder 279: 14)
    - W/42. Clippings on the Minister of the Wafd, 1931-1936 (Box-folder 279: 15)
    - W/50. Notes of Sadeq Henen from his trip to England, undated (Box-folder 279: 16)
    - W/51. Notes on the National Front, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 279: 17)
    - W/52. Correspondence and writings on the role of women in the Wafd movement, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 279: 18)
    - W/54. Open letter, 1911 (Box-folder 279: 19)